Guide to the Right Wing Pamphlet collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Right wing pamphlet collection
1917-2010
MS 775
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
7.42
(18 boxes)
An artificial collection of pamphlets containing "conservative, reactionary, or right wing" publications on a wide range of topics including: China, anti-communism, Christian groups, race relations, and economics, 1917-2010.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from the William R. Johnson Papers at the Yale Divinity Library, and other accessions; accession 2016-M-017 transferred from the Kaplanoff Librarian for American History, 2015.
Biographical / Historical
The core of these papers came from William R. Johnson (1878-1967), a Methodist missionary who lived in China from 1906 to 1942*. Caught in the Far East at the outbreak of World War II, he was repatriated to the United States in 1942 on the exchange ship, the Gripsholm. Following his arrival, he travelled and lectured extensively in the United States on the menace of Communist China and maintained an active interest in Chinese affairs to the end of his life. The collection reflects this interest in its rich array of brochures, leaflets, circular letters and publications of the many committees and individuals who were active in opposing recognition of Communist China. Of special note is the large collection of circular letters from Alfred Kohlberg, known as "Mr. China Lobby," who also headed the American China Policy Committee.
Johnson also subscribed to many conservative journals and news-letters, and received literature from a variety of individuals and tiny organizations devoted to special causes. The collection, as a consequence, contains many rare pieces of ephemeral conservative literature as well as newsletters from some of the better known figures, e.g. Gerald L.K. Smith, Elizabeth Dilling and Clarence Manion. As the reader will find, many of these items are emphatically underlined and sometimes accompanied by Johnson's marginal notes. While there are a few pieces added from other sources, the core of the collection reflects the issues of the 1950s and 1960s, providing a fascinating guide to the preoccupations, the style of thinking and the language of the right wing groups of that period.
*Johnson's personal papers are deposited at the Yale Divinity School, Manuscript Group Number 6.
Scope and Contents
The material is arranged alphabetically by subject, and groups concerned with a particular issue are placed together under the issue, rather than being listed separately by name. Under GUN CONTROL, for example, the reader will find literature of half a dozen different organizations. Three subjects which have a particularly large number of entries - ANTI-COMMUNISM; CHINA; and CHRISTIAN GROUPS - are further divided by prominent individuals and organizations.
The subject headings should be understood as indicating the predominant concern of these groups rather than as strictly defining their interests. Wherever they may start, most of these groups are united by a cluster of principles ranging over a variety of fields. Even so single-minded an organization as the Prohibition Party, for example, insists that although "many have the mistaken impression that the program of the Prohibition Party is very limited in scope, being almost entirely devoted to the prohibition of alchoholic beverages...its platform has been considerably expanded to include seventeen different planks." [Dr. Lowell H. Coate, National Chairman, "The Prohibition Challenge."]
The range of their interests can be very roughly gauged from the subject headings: e.g. gun control, fluoridation, mental health, race relations, immigration, foreign relations. One of the chief issues discussed under the heading FOREIGN RELATIONS is the United Nations, which these groups see as a danger to the sovereignty of the United States. Only two women's groups are represented - the Minute Women, and an antisemitic group which issued the publication Women's Voice.
Publications of ad hoc groups formed around a particular issue or person, are filed under that subject - e.g. Bricker Amendment, Pillion Amendment, General Edwin A. Walker. Periodicals issued by organizations are filed under the name of the organization, e.g. American Legion, Firing Line. In no case are the runs of periodicals comprehensive, but where there are a large number, the inclusive dates are given.
Antisemitism; Firearms -- Law and legislation; Anti-communist movements; Race relations; Vietnam War, 1961-1975; Right and Left (Political Science); China -- Foreign relations; China -- Politics and government; United States -- Politics and government; United States -- Foreign relations; Asia; Johnson, William R., 1878-1967
- PRINTED MATTER FROM THE JOHNSON COLLECTION, 1917-1966; Series I; 5' 10" (14 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  The printed matter from the Johnson Papers was acquired by Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library from the Divinity Library in 1976. It was then arranged with related items from other sources into fourteen boxes which form Series I of this collection. Right Wing pamphlets and periodicals of a similar character acquired after that date are added to the register in Series II which is arranged by subject.
  - Africa
    - Afro-Asian Educational Exchange, American Committee for Aid to Katanga...; et al., 1962-1964, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Katanga
      General note
      See: box 8, folder 144
  - Anti-Communism-General
    - Bibliography: booksellers' lists; individual advertisements; reading lists; reviews, 1953-1965, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Bibliography: booksellers' list-Caxton Printers, 1954-1961, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Bibliography: films, recordings, tapes, 1965 February 1-5, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Drama: Congressional Investigations, 1962 June 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Individuals
      - A-Z, miscellaneous, 1942-1965, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Bell, Don
        See: box 8, folder 134
      - Bern, Gregory C., 1951-1959 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Crippen, John K., undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
        See also: box 5, folder 73
      - Davison, Mary M., undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
        See also: box 6, folder 89
      - Deatherage, George E., undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Dilling, Elizabeth, 1952-1964, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Dresser, Robert B., 1953-1966, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Ernestine, Mathilde, 1949-1951, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - Everingham, Don
        See: box 8, folder 142 box 6, folder 99
      - Fischer, Ruth, 1946 September-October (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - Flynn, John T., 1947-1949, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
        See also: box 5, folder 72
      - Hance, Mrs. J. H., 1953 October 20 (Box 1, Folder 16)
        See also: box 3, folder 42
      - Hoover, John Edgar, 1952-1960, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - Jenner, William E., 1951-1958, undated, 1954-1956 (Box 2, Folder 18-19)
      - Johnson, William R., 1945-1961, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
      - Judd, Walter H., 1943-1959 (Box 2, Folder 21)
      - Kamp, Joseph P., 1952-1956 (Box 2, Folder 22)
      - Kirkpatrick, Frank, 1953 May-November (Box 2, Folder 23)
      - Kohlberg, Alfred, 1944-1956 (Box 2, Folder 24-28)
      - Kohlberg, Alfred, 1957-1960, undated (Box 3, Folder 29-31)
      - Kohlberg, Alfred Memoranda, notes, printed matter, 1946-1960, undated (Box 3, Folder 32)
        See also: box 10, folder 159-165
      - Kornfeder, Joseph Zack, 1952-1954, undated (Box 3, Folder 33)
      - Kuhn, Irene Corbally, 1954 August-October (Box 3, Folder 34)
      - Lee, J. Bracken: The American Statesman, 1958-1959, undated (Box 3, Folder 35)
      - Loeb, William: Manchester Union Leader, 1955-1964 (Box 3, Folder 36)
      - McCarthy, Joe, 1947-1954, undated (Box 3, Folder 37)
      - McIntire, Carl
        See: box 11, folder 198
      - Manion, Clarence E., 1956-1964, undated (Box 3, Folder 38)
      - Matthews, J. B., 1941-1955, undated (Box 3, Folder 39)
      - Oliver, Rivalo Pendleton, 1959-1964, undated (Box 3, Folder 40)
      - Philbrick, Herbert A., 1965 August-Sep, undated (Box 3, Folder 41)
        See also: box 8, folder 144
      - Phillips, J. C., 1950-1954, undated (Box 3, Folder 42)
        See also: box 1, folder 16
      - Poling, Daniel, 1956 Apr, undated (Box 3, Folder 43)
        See also: box 4, folder 59
      - Rand, Ayn: Objectivist Newsletter, 1962 June (Box 3, Folder 44)
      - Rumely, Edward A.
        See: box 5, folder 78
      - Schwarz, Frederick C., 1957-1966, undated (Box 3, Folder 45)
      - Siegrist, Bob, 1957-1958, undated (Box 3, Folder 46)
      - Smith, Gerald L. K., 1961-1963, undated, 1949-1974, undated (Box 3, Folder 47-48)
      - Smith, Gerald L. K., 1962-1963, undated (Box 4, Folder 49)
      - Smith, Gerald L. K.: The Cross and the Flag, 1965-1966, undated (Box 4, Folder 50)
      - Smoot, Dan: Dan Smoot Report, 1953-1962, undated (Box 4, Folder 51)
      - Sokolsky, George, 1954-1958 (Box 4, Folder 52)
      - Stone, Willis E.
        See: box 4, folder 69
      - Waters, Agnes, 1948-1957 (Box 4, Folder 53)
      - Welch, Robert, 1959 May 28 (Box 4, Folder 54)
      - Williams, Robert H., 1949-1954, undated (Box 4, Folder 55)
      - Winegarner, Charles W. (nephew of Gerald L.K. Smith), 1963 October 16, undated (Box 4, Folder 56)
        See also: box 5, folder 75 box 11, folder 179
    - Organizations
      - A-Z, miscellaneous, 1950-1966, undated (Box 4, Folder 57)
      - Abraham Lincoln National Republican Club, 1944-1958, undated (Box 4, Folder 58)
      - All-American Conference to Combat Communism, 1950-1958, undated (Box 4, Folder 59)
      - American Coalition of Patriotic Societies: Report to America, 1958-1963, undated (Box 4, Folder 60)
        See also: box 11, folder 185
      - American Conservative Union, undated (Box 4, Folder 61)
      - American Eagle Publishing Co., 1961-1964, undated (Box 4, Folder 62)
      - American Economic Foundation, undated (Box 4, Folder 63)
      - American Flag Committee, 1952-1966 (Box 4, Folder 64)
        See also: box 13, folder 219
      - American Flag Committee; Newsletter, 1962-1966 (Box 4, Folder 65)
      - American Jewish League Against Communism, 1962 February-March (Box 4, Folder 66)
        See also: box 2, folder 24-28 box 3, folder 29-31 box 4, folder 66
      - American Legion: Firing Line, 1950-1957, undated (Box 4, Folder 67)
      - American Mercury (reprints), 1934-1963, undated (Box 4, Folder 68)
      - American Progress Foundation, 1957-1958, undated (Box 4, Folder 69)
      - American Public Relations Forum, 1955-1959 (Box 4, Folder 70)
      - Americans for Constitutional Action, 1958, undated (Box 4, Folder 71)
      - America's Future, 1944-1966, undated (Box 5, Folder 72)
      - Anti-Communist League of America, 1956-1965, undated (Box 5, Folder 73)
      - Cinema Educational Guild, 1957-1962, undated (Box 5, Folder 74)
      - Citizens Congressional Committee, 1963-1964 (Box 5, Folder 75)
        See also: box 4, folder 47-48
      - Citizens' Councils of America, 1954-1957, undated (Box 5, Folder 76)
      - Citizens' Councils of America: The Councilor, 1964-1965 (Box 5, Folder 77)
      - Committee for Constitutional Government, 1944-1957, undated (Box 5, Folder 78)
      - Committee for Constitutional Government: Fighters for Freedom, 1949-1950, undated (Box 5, Folder 79)
      - Committee for Constitutional Government: Paul Revere Messages, undated (Box 5, Folder 80)
      - Committee for Constitutional Government: Spotlight for the Nation, 1951-1957, undated (Box 5, Folder 81)
      - Committee for Public Affairs: Washington Report, 1961-1963, undated (Box 5, Folder 82)
      - Communications Network for America, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 83)
      - Congress of Freedom (Box 5, Folder 84)
      - Congress of Freedom: The Greater Nebraskan, 1957-1963 (Box 5, Folder 85)
      - Congress of Freedom: Bulletins, 1953-1954 (Box 5, Folder 85)
      - Congress of Freedom: Freedom Facts, 1957-1960 (Box 5, Folder 85)
      - Conservative Society of America, 1957-1964, undated (Box 5, Folder 86)
      - Constitution Party, 1954-1962, undated (Box 5, Folder 87)
      - Council for Statehood: Open Letters, 1963-1966, undated (Box 6, Folder 88)
        See also: box 6, folder 90
      - Council for Statehood, 1958-1964, undated (Box 6, Folder 89)
      - Council on American Relations, 1958-1961, undated (Box 6, Folder 90)
      - Counterattack, 1950-1961, undated (Box 6, Folder 91)
      - The Cross and the Flag
        See: box 4, folder 47-48
      - Defenders, Inc., 1955-1964, undated (Box 6, Folder 92)
      - Defenders of the American Constitution: Task Force, 1954-1966 (Box 6, Folder 93)
      - Federation for Constitutional Government, 1956-1959, undated (Box 6, Folder 94)
      - Fighters for Freedom
      - For America, 1954-1966, undated (Box 6, Folder 95)
      - Foundation for Economic Education, 1938-1965, undated (Box 6, Folder 96)
      - Foundation for Social Research, 1950-1954, undated (Box 6, Folder 97)
      - Free Men Speak, 1956-1957, undated (Box 6, Folder 98)
        See also: box 7, folder 106
      - Freedom Club of Downtown Chicago, 1952-1955, undated (Box 6, Folder 99)
      - The Freedom Press, 1965-1966 (Box 6, Folder 100)
      - Freedoms Foundation, 1952-1955, undated (Box 6, Folder 101)
      - Friends of Democracy: Democracy's Battle, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 102)
      - Headlines
        See: box 2, folder 22
      - Human Events, 1944-1964, undated, 1953-1960 (Box 6, Folder 103-104)
      - Human Events, 1944-1966 (Box 7, Folder 105)
      - The Independent American, 1958-1963 (Box 7, Folder 106)
      - The Independent American, 1964-1966, undated (Box 7, Folder 107)
        See also: Box 6, folder 98
      - International Youth for Freedom (IYFF), 1965 (Box 7, Folder 108)
      - John Birch Society, 1962, undated (Box 7, Folder 109)
      - Keep America Committee, 1949-1954, undated (Box 7, Folder 110)
      - Keep America Free Council: The Rampart, 1963, undated (Box 7, Folder 111)
      - Liberty and Property, 1955-1957, undated (Box 7, Folder 112)
      - Liberty and Property: Right, 1955-1959, undated (Box 7, Folder 113)
      - Liberty Lobby, 1957-1966, undated (Box 7, Folder 114)
      - Liberty Lobby: Liberty Letter, 1960-1966 (Box 7, Folder 115)
      - Life Lines, 1960-1961, undated (Box 7, Folder 116)
      - Minute Women: Newsletter, 1954-1957, undated (Box 7, Folder 117)
      - Moral Rearmament, 1949-1962, undated (Box 7, Folder 118)
      - National Collegiate MacArthur Clubs: The American Student, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 119)
      - National Economic Council, 1947-1957, undated (Box 7, Folder 120)
      - National Republic, 1953-1954 (Box 7, Folder 121)
      - National Reprint Service, 1955-1966, undated (Box 7, Folder 122)
      - Nationalist Conservative Party, undated (Box 7, Folder 123)
      - National States Rights Party, 1950-1966, undated (Box 8, Folder 124)
      - Ohio Coalition of Patriotic Societies, 1954-1964, undated (Box 8, Folder 125)
        See also: box 3, folder 33
      - Ohio Committee of Endorsers, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 126)
      - Ohio State University Conservative Club, 1962-1965, undated (Box 8, Folder 127)
        See also: box 8, folder 125
      - Pennsylvania Weekly Review, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 128)
      - Protect America League, 1952-1955, undated (Box 8, Folder 129)
      - Public Action, Inc., 1958-1965, undated (Box 8, Folder 130)
      - Right
        See: box 7, folder 112
      - Society of Red Haters, (1951), undated (Box 8, Folder 131)
      - Sons of the American Revolution, 1954-1957, undated (Box 8, Folder 132)
      - Time for Truth Press: Closer up, 1945-1964, undated (Box 8, Folder 133)
      - Time for Truth Press: Don Bell Reports, 1957-1965, undated (Box 8, Folder 134)
      - Truth, Inc., undated (Box 8, Folder 135)
      - United States Day Committee, 1954-1956, undated (Box 8, Folder 136)
      - U.S. Flag Committee, 1961-1962, undated (Box 8, Folder 137)
      - Watch Washington Club, 1964, undated (Box 8, Folder 138)
      - We, the People, 1955-1963, undated (Box 8, Folder 139-141)
      - We, the People: The Fact Finder, 1952-1956, undated (Box 8, Folder 142)
      - We, the People: Free Enterprise, 1956-1961 (Box 8, Folder 143)
      - Young Americans for Freedom, 1961-1964, undated (Box 8, Folder 144)
  - Anti-Semitism
    - A - Z, miscellaneous, 1917-1961, undated (Box 8, Folder 145)
    - Allen, Marilyn R., 1946-1949, undated (Box 8, Folder 146)
    - American Nationalist, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 147)
    - Common Sense, 1950-1966, undated (Box 8, Folder 148)
    - Women's Voice, 1949-1957, undated (Box 9, Folder 149)
    - Women's Voice: miscellaneous reprints, 1945-1958, undated (Box 9, Folder 150)
  - For other items on Anti-semitism (Box 9, Folder 150)
    see also: box 1, folder 11 box 2, folder 22 box 8, folder 133 box 8, folder 134 box 8, folder 124 box 9, folder 153 box 12, folder 194
  - Bricker Amendment, 1954-1955, undated (Box 9, Folder 151)
  - British Groups, 1944-1946 (Box 9, Folder 152)
  - Canadian Groups
    - The Canadian Intelligence Service, 1956-1964, undated (Box 9, Folder 153)
    - Christian Action Movement, 1957-1963 (Box 9, Folder 154)
  - China
    - Background information: a compilation by J. B. Moody, 1928-1951, undated (Box 9, Folder 155)
    - Miscellaneous publications, 1947-1966, undated (Box 9, Folder 156)
    - Reports, memoranda, analyses, speeches, 1933-1966, undated (Box 9, Folder 157)
    - Individuals
      - Fitch, Geraldine, 1933-1966 (Box 9, Folder 158)
      - Kohlberg, Arthur
        See: box 2, folder 24-28 box 3, folder 29-31
    - Organizations
      - American China Policy Association, 1933-1960 (Box 10, Folder 159-165)
      - China Lobby, 1952-1966, undated (Box 10, Folder 166)
      - Church Committee for China Relief, 1943 (Box 10, Folder 167)
      - Citizens' Foreign Relations Committee
        See: box 13, folder 208
      - Committee to Defend America by Aiding Anti-Communist China, 1949-1952, undated (Box 10, Folder 168)
      - Committee for a Democratic Far Eastern Policy, 1948-1949, undated (Box 10, Folder 169)
      - Committee for One Million, 1951-1965, undated (Box 10, Folder 170)
      - Communist Party, Directive of, 1949
        See: box 2, folder 24-28
  - Christian Groups
    - A - Z, miscellaneous, 1941-1964, undated (Box 10, Folder 171)
    - American Council of Christian Churches, 1952-1965, undated (Box 10, Folder 172)
    - American Council of Christian Laymen, 1949-1959, undated (Box 11, Folder 173)
    - American Council of Christian Laymen: Challenge, 1950-1959 (Box 11, Folder 174)
    - Christian Anti-Communism Crusade
      See: box 3, folder 45
    - Christian Crusade, 1960-1965, undated (Box 11, Folder 175)
    - Christianform, 1949-1958 (Box 11, Folder 176)
      See also: box 6, folder 103-104
    - Christian Freedom Foundation: Christian Economics, 1950-1955, undated (Box 11, Folder 177)
    - Christian Nationalist Crusade
    - Christian Victory Center, 1953-1955 (Box 11, Folder 178)
    - Christian Youth Against Communism (CYAC), 1961-1965, undated (Box 11, Folder 179)
    - Church League of America (Box 11, Folder 180)
      See also: box 13, folder 213
    - Church League of America: News and Views, 1945-1966 (Box 11, Folder 181)
    - Circuit Riders, 1933-1962, undated, 1929-1960, undated, 1934-1961, undated (Box 11, Folder 182-184)
    - Committee of Christian Laymen, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 185)
      See also: box 4, folder 60
    - Congregational Christian Churches, 1953 (Box 11, Folder 186)
    - Defenders of the Christian Faith, 1964, undated (Box 11, Folder 187)
    - International Christian Relief, 1961-1965 (Box 11, Folder 188)
      See also: box 12, folder 190
    - International Christian Youth, 1963-1966, undated (Box 12, Folder 189)
    - International Council of Christian Churches (ICCC), 1957-1965, undated (Box 12, Folder 190)
      See also: box 10, folder 172
    - Lutheran Church: The Epistle, 1963-1964 (Box 12, Folder 191)
    - Methodist Church, 1934-1961, undated (Box 12, Folder 192)
    - Controversy in the Methodist Church, 1948-1954
      See also: box 11, folder 182-184
    - Methodist Federation for Social Action (MESA), 1928-1954, undated (Box 12, Folder 193)
    - National Federation of Christian Laymen, 1955-1957, undated (Box 12, Folder 194)
    - Protestants and Other Americans, 1952-1954, undated (Box 12, Folder 195)
    - Spiritual Mobilization, 1954-1960, undated (Box 12, Folder 196)
    - The Tablet (clippings), 1956-1961 (Box 12, Folder 197)
    - Twentieth-Century Reformation Hour (Rev. Carl McIntire), 1962-1966 (Box 12, Folder 198)
    - Other publications by Reverend Carl McIntire, 1957-1965, undated (Box 12, Folder 199)
  - Communist Literature, 1928-1964, undated (Box 12, Folder 200)
  - Currency Reform, 1946-1965, undated (Box 12, Folder 201)
  - East (Far East)
    - American Asian Educational Exchange, Inc. (Box 12, Folder 202)
    - American Committee for Non-Participation in Japanese Agression (Box 12, Folder 202)
    - Korean Cultural and Freedom Foundation, Inc. (Box 12, Folder 202)
    - Pan Pacific Centers, 1948-1965, undated (Box 12, Folder 202)
    - Far Eastern Newsletter. (Box 12, Folder 203)
    - Institute of Pacific Relations controversy, 1942-1952 (Box 13, Folder 204)
      See also: box 13, folder 217
  - Eastern Europe, 1917-1963, undated (Box 13, Folder 205)
    See also: box 1, folder 14
  - Education, 1947-1963, undated (Box 13, Folder 206)
  - Fluoridation, 1955-1964, undated (Box 13, Folder 207)
  - Foreign relations
    - A - Z, miscellaneous publications by individuals, 1941-1963, undated (Box 13, Folder 208)
    - Miscellaneous publications by organizations, 1952-1973, undated (Box 13, Folder 209)
    - Americans for National Security (Box 13, Folder 209)
    - American Security Council (Box 13, Folder 209)
    - Citizens' Foreign Relations Committee (Box 13, Folder 209)
    - Committee of Endorsers (Box 13, Folder 209)
    - Trade Policy Committee (Box 13, Folder 209)
    - Miscellaneous publications by organizations, 1953-1963, undated (Box 13, Folder 210)
  - Gun Control, 1957-(1958), undated (Box 12, Folder 211)
    See also: box 5, folder 84
  - Hawaii, (1956?) (Box 12, Folder 212)
  - Immigration, 1940-1953, undated (Box 12, Folder 213)
    See also: box 6, folder 93 box 6, folder 94 box 9, folder 149
  - Kennedy, John F., 1957 (Box 12, Folder 214)
  - Kent, Tyler
    See: box 14, folder 232
  - Latin America
    - Committee for the Monroe Doctrine, 1962-1965, undated (Box 13, Folder 215)
    - Miscellaneous publications Citizens' Committee for a Free Cuba Committee on Pan American Policy, 1961-1966, undated (Box 13, Folder 216)
  - Lattimore, Owen, 1946-1952, undated (Box 13, Folder 217)
  - Medicine
    - Hoxsey Method
      See: box 6, folder 92
    - "Psycho-vaxeen", 1959-1962, undated (Box 13, Folder 218)
  - Mental Health, 1948-1965, undated (Box 13, Folder 219)
  - New Deal, 1943-1949 (Box 13, Folder 220)
  - Oxnam, G. Bromley, 1931-1957, undated (Box 13, Folder 221)
  - Panama Canal
    See: box 13, folder 215
  - Pillion Resolution, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 222)
  - Prohibition, 1956-1964, undated (Box 14, Folder 223)
  - Race Relations
    - Blacks, 1954-1963, undated (Box 14, Folder 224)
    - Japanese, 1918-1921, undated (Box 14, Folder 225)
  - Refugees: International Rescue Committee, 1951-(post 1960), undated (Box 14, Folder 226)
  - Republican Party, 1956-1965, undated (Box 14, Folder 227)
    See also: Box 1, Bern, Gregory G.
    See also: box 4, folder 58 box 8, folder 128
  - "Right to Work"
    See: box 14, folder 299
  - Roosevelt, Franklin D.
    See: box 13, folder 220